<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ranjan Khyadad</title>
    <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ranjan Khyadad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 10:00:26 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Habits - Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/atomic-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 10:00:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/atomic-habits/</guid>
      <description>Chapter1 Growth   1% improvement everyday ,makes you 37 times better in a year, while getting worse 1% everyday will take you back to ZERO. Compounding works the same way as money.
  Small changes matter a lot. Results don&amp;rsquo;t come immediately. So, don&amp;rsquo;t slide into bad habits or previous habits. Remember, a small degree shift in the angle makes a larger difference in the direction.
  Focus only on the current trajectory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/linux-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 13:37:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/linux-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Shortcuts
Auto-Complete
[TAB] - Initiates auto-complete. This will suggest to us different options based on the STDIN we provide. These can be specific suggestions like directories in our current working environment, commands starting with the same number of characters we already typed, or options. Cursor Movement
[CTRL] + A - Move the cursor to the beginning of the current line.
[CTRL] + E - Move the cursor to the end of the current line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey</title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/my-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 15:45:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/my-journey/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks,
This is my first post on this website. I want to start this journey by telling you all who I am and how my career has been so far.
I am Ranjan, an ECE graduate from BMS College of Engineering in 2017. I am a CyberSecurity analyst and a software developer, who&amp;rsquo;s always in search of new things to learn and experiment.
Chapter 1: I started my professional career in Wipro in 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is
Ranjan Khyadad. I safeguard companies from cyber threats and write code. I am a CyberSecurity Engineer, specialising in Cyber Defense using Microsoft Security Suite. I currently work as a CyberSecurity Senior Analyst at Mindtree.
I build meaningful solutions to real world problems using my unique set of multi-domain skills. I write my code in Python.
For any professional queries, reach out to me on Mail or send me a message on LinkedIn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Get in touch!   Mail
  LinkedIn
  Twitter
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
