<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Ranjan Khyadad</title>
    <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Ranjan Khyadad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 13:00:55 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/secure-your-web-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 13:00:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/secure-your-web-apps/</guid>
      <description>This is my attempt to understand the basic security flaws a web developer might encounter while developing a web application.
This blog is just my takeaways from the Hack the Box&amp;rsquo;s Introduction to Web Applications module. Please refer OWASP Top Ten for the detailed list.
The top 20 most common mistakes web developers make that cause vulnerabilities are:
 Permitting Invalid Data to Enter the Database Focusing on the System as a Whole Establishing Personally Developed Security Methods Treating Security to be Your Last Step Developing Plain Text Password Storage Creating Weak Passwords Storing Unencrypted Data in the Database Depending Excessively on the Client Side Being Too Optimistic Permitting Variables via the URL Path Name Trusting third-party code Hard-coding backdoor accounts Unverified SQL injections Remote file inclusions Insecure data handling Failing to encrypt data properly Not using a secure cryptographic system Ignoring layer 8 Review user actions Web Application Firewall misconfigurations  These lead to our OWASP Top Ten:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Dorking</title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/google-dorking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 13:54:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/google-dorking/</guid>
      <description>I came across this article about Google dorking.
With Google&amp;rsquo;s tremendous web-crawling capabilities, it can index almost anything within your website, including sensitive information.This means you could be exposing too much information about your web technologies, usernames, passwords, and general vulnerabilities without even knowing it.
Definition: Google “Dorking” is the practice of using Google to find vulnerable web applications and servers by using native Google search engine capabilities.
Google Hacking Database has a list of all the dorking scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning How to Learn</title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/learning-how-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 20:15:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/learning-how-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>The process of &amp;ldquo;learning how to learn&amp;rdquo; is complicated. Most of us have never truly learned how to learn effectively.
This useful excerpt is from a module on Hack the Box.
Learning Efficiency The sheer size of the information security field is overwhelming to any new learner. There is a lot to learn and many topics to cover.
The primary and most difficult objective we must overcome is the combination of our knowledge, adaptation, and new information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Habits - Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/atomic-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 10:00:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/atomic-habits/</guid>
      <description>Chapter1 Growth   1% improvement everyday ,makes you 37 times better in a year, while getting worse 1% everyday will take you back to ZERO. Compounding works the same way as money.
  Small changes matter a lot. Results don&amp;rsquo;t come immediately. So, don&amp;rsquo;t slide into bad habits or previous habits. Remember, a small degree shift in the angle makes a larger difference in the direction.
  Focus only on the current trajectory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/linux-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 13:37:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/linux-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Shortcuts
Auto-Complete
[TAB] - Initiates auto-complete. This will suggest to us different options based on the STDIN we provide. These can be specific suggestions like directories in our current working environment, commands starting with the same number of characters we already typed, or options. Cursor Movement
[CTRL] + A - Move the cursor to the beginning of the current line.
[CTRL] + E - Move the cursor to the end of the current line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey</title>
      <link>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/my-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 15:45:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ranjankhyadad.github.io/blog/my-journey/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks,
This is my first post on this website. I want to start this journey by telling you all who I am and how my career has been so far.
I am Ranjan, an ECE graduate from BMS College of Engineering in 2017. I am a CyberSecurity analyst and a software developer, who&amp;rsquo;s always in search of new things to learn and experiment.
Chapter 1: I started my professional career in Wipro in 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
